Guide to music ane the Black Church
Music and the Black Church
Oral History of American Music
Music and the Black Church
2022 2023
MBC
Oral History of American Music
15 Computer Files
15.2 gigabytes
Shelley, Braxton D.
Scope and Contents
A collection of video interviews with leaders of music in the Black church, including pastors, music ministers, gospel artists, and choir directors. These interviews were conducted by students in the Yale University class The Gospel Imagination, taught by Prof. Braxton Shelley.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. The finding aid includes links to stream most interviews online via Oral History of American Music's (OHAM) AV access system, Aviary. Yale users can login to Aviary using their Yale University ID, to stream these interviews without restriction. Other users are able to request access to interviews directly through Aviary. For access instructions, and to request transcripts of an interview, see OHAM's website.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by surname.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
.mp4 and .mov files
Gospel music; Gospel musicians; Church music African American churches
- Baker, Barbara W.
  - Baker, Barbara W., 2023 May 8; MBC 14 a; Brown, Carlos, Jr., 2001-; 1 Computer File; 1.12; Approximate running time: 59 mins
    Interview location
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Siver Spring, MD and interviewer in New Haven, CT.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    .mp4 file
    Baker, Barbara W. (Barbara Wesley)
- Brooks, Kent
  - Brooks, Kent, 2022 May 5; MBC 1 a; Willis, John, 1997-; 1 Computer File; 1.61 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 110 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Evanston, IL and interviewer in New Haven, CT.
    Brooks, Kent R.
- Clayton, Lisa
  - Clayton, Lisa, 2023 May 4; 15 a-b; Addison, Ceily; 2 Computer Files; 284 megabytes; Approximate running time: 50 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat with interviewee in Storres, CT (?) and interviewer in New Haven, CT.
    .mp4 files
    Clayton, Lisa (Gospel Musician)
- Davis, Leo, Jr.
  - Davis, Leo, Jr., 2022 May 9; MBC 5 a; Prescod, Nedelka; 1 Computer File; 1 gigabyte; Approximate running time: 66 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Memphis, TN and interviewer in Brooklyn, NY
    Davis, Leo, Jr.
- Dickenson, Omar
  - Dickenson, Omar, 2022 May 11; MBC 10 a; Allen, Justin, 1992-; 1 Computer File; 440 megabytes; Approximate running time: 53 minutes
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Hampton, VA and interviewer in New Haven, CT
    Dickenson, Omar
- Graves, Avis D.
  - Graves, Avis D., 2022 May 9; MBC 6 a; Roberts, Rachel, 1999-; 1 Computer File; 909 megabytes; Approximate running time: 72 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Cleveland, OH and interviewer in New Haven, CT.
    Graves, Avis D.
- Hines, Charletta
  - Hines, Charletta, 2022 May 10; MBC 8 a-c; Byrne, Clare; 3 Computer Files; 513 megabytes; Approximate running time: 60 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Durham, NC and interviewer in Guilford, CT
    Hines, Charletta
- McNeill, Tony
  - McNeill, Tony, 2022 May 9; MBC 7 a; Valor, Pau Ruis; 1 Computer File; 368 megabytes; Approximate running time: 60 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Rock Hill, SC and interviewer in New Haven, CT
    McNeill, Tony
- Ministering Through the Arts: Tradition and Innovation, 2023 October 26; MBC 19 a; Shelley, Braxton D.; White-Clayton, Diane L.; Garrett, Joyce; Harris, Will (Gospel Musician); Jackson-Sago, Barbara; Moore-Copeland, L'Tanya; Owens, Walter; Robinson, Eddie A.; 1 Computer File; 49.9 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 131 mins
  Scope and Contents
  Panel convened in New Haven by the Interdisciplinary Program in Music and the Black Church at the Yale Institute of Sacred Music. Opening remarks by Martin Jean and introduction by Braxton Shelley.
  .mov file
- Moore-Copeland, L'Tanya
  - Moore-Copeland, L'Tanya, 2023 May 9; MBC 16 a; Hester, Amaris; 1 Computer File; 575 megabytes; Approximate running time: 52 mins.
    Interview conducted via videochat with interviewee in Atlanta, GA (?) and interviewer in New Haven, CT.
    Moore-Copeland, L'Tanya
- Pace, Kay
  - Pace, Kay, 2023 May 4; MBC 17 a; McFadden, Christoph'; 1 Computer File; 905 megabytes; Approximate running time: 73 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Union City, GA and interviewer in New Haven, CT.
    Pace, Kay
- Pollard, Deborah Smith
  - Pollard, Deborah Smith, 2023 May 5; MBC 18 a; Byrne, Clare; 1 Computer File; 517 megabytes; Approximate running time: 61 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Detroit, MI and interviewer in Guildford, CT.
    Pollard, Deborah Smith
- Sellers-Battle, Crystal
  - Sellers-Battle, Crystal, 2022 May 5; MBC 2 a; Brown, Zada; 1 Computer File; 291 megabytes; Approximate running time: 60 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Huntington, PA and interviewer in New Haven, CT
    Sellers-Battle, Crystal
- Thomas, Deborah Manning
  - Thomas, Deborah Manning, 2023 May 4; MBC 11 a; Azumah, Dzidedi; 1 Computer File; 510 megabytes; Approximate running time: 56 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat.
    .m4a file
    Manning, Deborah, (Gospel singer)
- Turner, Patrice E.
  - Turner, Patrice E., 2022 May 6; MBC 3 a; McCoy, Omena; 1 Computer File; 880 megabytes; Approximate running time: 50 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Atlanta, GA, and interviewer in New Haven, CT
    Turner, Patrice E.
- White-Clayton, Diane
  - White-Clayton, Diane, 2023 May 6; MBC 12 a; Fore-Ravelo, Tamara; 1 Computer File; 1.5 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 80 minutes
    White-Clayton, Diane L.
- Williams, Oscar, Jr.
  - Williams, Oscar, Jr., 2022 May 10; MBC 9 a; Kankam, Amma; 1 Computer File; 6 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 46 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with intervier in unknown location and interviewee in New Haven, CT
    Williams, Oscar, Jr.
- Williams, Vanessa R.
  - Williams, Vanessa R., 2023 May 2; MBC 15 a-b; Eteme, Vyann; 3 Computer Files; 657 megabytes; Approximate running time: 108 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat
    .m4a files
    Williams, Vanessa R.
- Wilson, G. Preston
  - Wilson, G. Preston, 2022 May 6; MBC 4 a; Frodyma, Archer; 1 Computer File; 633 megabytes; Approximate running time: 46 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Lawrenceville, NJ and interviewer in New Haven, CT
    Wilson, G. Preston